Cristóbal Andrés Contreras Beltrán

Computer Science Degree - Full-Stack Developer

+56 9 95182311

github.com/AsCraftC

Bē /AsCraftC

Profile

in /in/cristobal-contreras

Recently graduated engineer with a background in many branches of computer science and project management. Strong ability to learn software development, database and IT support. Experienced in user-focused technical support. Specialized in Frontend development, user experience (UX), SQL and NoSQL database management and and background knowledge of **Backend**

Areas of Expertise

Network Administration - UX/UI Design - Frontend development - Database design and maintenance - Data Analyst -Gamification - IT technical support - GNU/Linux - Windows Administrator

Professional Experience

Frontend Developer, iDEAUFRO

Temuco, Chile 06/2023 - 12/2023

- Frontend project requirements gathering of 1 project focusing frontend needs.
- Use of Figma to create wireframes and interactive mockups applying a total of 7 views.
- Web UI design and development applying User Centered Design over 4 iterations.
- Backend integration and server deployment.

IT technical support, ASESORIAS Y GESTIONES TECNOLOGICAS SPA La Araucania, Chile 02/2021 - 04/2024

- Printer diagnostics and repair of hardware and/or software problems.
- Configuration and validation of printer usage on LAN networks.
- Configuration of printing equipment usability and user usability training.
- Optimization of the use of printer equipment, which increased user productivity and reduced the number of problems that required technical intervention.

Online Courses & Certifications

- Personal Cybersecurity Route (May. 2024) Platzi
- Git & GitHub Professional course (Jun. 2024) Platzi

Education

Ingeniería civil Informática Universidad de La Frontera

Temuco, Chile 2018-2023

Relevant Courses: Network Workshop, Computer Science 1 y 2, Databases 1 y 2, Requirements engineering, Computer Auditing, UX design, Cryptography and privacy, Software quality management, **Project formulation and evaluation**, Information Security, Internet of Things(IoT)

Skills

- Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MariaDB
- Programming Languages & other: C#, GDScript, Python, Java, SQL, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, LateX
- Software: Excel, Figma, VSCode, git, Node, Unity, Godot, Android Studio, Flutter, IntelliJ IDEA, Windows, GNU/linux, React, springboot
- Soft Skills: IEEE-830 requirement documentation, UML diagrams and documentation, Unit tests, Responsive design, API REST consumption, Scrum methodology, Effective Communication, Personal and professional courtesy, Risk management, Self-management, Class B Chilean driver's license

Languages

- English Conversational [Intermediate] B1 (UFRO) Spanish [Native]
- English [technical]